The greatest story Hitchcock ever told
Hitchcock/Truffaut is a documentary film directed by Kent Jones.
Filmmakers discuss the legacy of Alfred Hitchcock and the book “Hitchcock/Truffaut” (“Le
cinéma selon Hitchcock”), written by François Truffaut and published in 1966.
Narrator (voice), played by Bob Balaban.
Self, played by Wes Anderson.
Self, played by Olivier Assayas.
Self, played by Peter Bogdanovich.
Self, played by Arnaud Desplechin.
Self, played by David Fincher.
Hitchcock/Truffaut is a 1966 book by François Truffaut about Alfred Hitchcock,
originally released in French as Le Cinéma selon Alfred Hitchcock.
First published by Éditions Robert Laffont, it is based on a 1962 dialogue between Hitchcock and Truffaut,
in which the two directors spent a week in a room at Universal Studios talking about movies.
The book walks through all of Hitchcock's films, from
his early British period to Torn Curtain.
After Hitchcock's death, Truffaut updated the book with a new preface and final chapter on Hitchcock's
later films Topaz, Frenzy and Family Plot, as well as his unrealized project The Short Night.